<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>links on Новости электронного книгоиздания</title>
    <link>/tags/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in links on Новости электронного книгоиздания</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 13:23:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Полезные ссылки лета 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-09-13-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 13:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-09-13-a/</guid>
      <description>Пропрокрастинировал, а вот уже и ссылок набежало.
Июнь Использование РИНЦ и Science Index для анализа и оценки научной деятельности
As the World Cup Approaches, PEN Authors Press Moscow for Oleg Sentsov&amp;rsquo;s Release
Romanian Author-Politician Ovidiu Raeţchi Launches a &amp;lsquo;Pact for Books&amp;rsquo; Вот как надо поддерживать чтение! А не вот этот весь год литературы.
Ъ: Вице-президент &amp;ldquo;Просвещения&amp;rdquo; Наталья Фирсова: «Преждевременно говорить о каких-либо пересмотрах судебных актов»
Роспатент аннулировал товарный знак «Просвещения» – Бизнес – Коммерсантъ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Всякие полезные ссылки мая 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-06-04-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 12:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-06-04-a/</guid>
      <description>Audible is Giving Away a Kindle With New Annual Membership | The Digital Reader Аукцион немыслимой щедрости.
Amazon Revives the Book of the Month Club Idea With Prime Book Box | The Digital Reader
eBooks have yet to take off in Vietnam
Storytel’s Latin American ambitions. Brazil, Mexico, Argentina and Colombia for 2019? - The New Publishing Standard
9 out of 10 Norwegians read books. 3 out of 4 buy from physical book stores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Всякие, в том числе полезные, ссылки апреля 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-05-04-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 12:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-05-04-a/</guid>
      <description>Publishers Confront Slow Growth Самые большие чувствуют себя не очень, поменьше — более/менее.
Carmen&amp;rsquo;s Page: Microsoft eBooks is a thing? История о том, как автор не смог найти файл купленной им в Microsoft Store книги у себя в компе.
Amazon is Shutting Down Its Crowd-Sourcing Platform, Kindle Scout | The Digital Reader Что и неудивительно.
Утверждён Порядок доставки, хранения, учёта обязательного экземпляра печатного издания в электронной форме
A World Accounting: The WIPO-IPA Global Publishing Pilot Survey Забавный обзор с совершенно адскими данными из Китая.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Полезные ссылки марта 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-04-04-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 09:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-04-04-d/</guid>
      <description>B&amp;amp;N Reports Revenues Down 5.3% in 3rd Fiscal Quarter | The Digital Reader
AAP Reports Publisher Revenues Up 1.7% Through October 2017 | The Digital Reader
На издательском рынке создана новая отраслевая организация Речь о печатной прессе — все ассоциации слились. В одну.
Пиратов не будут преследовать за распространение книг нобелевского лауреата | РОСКОМСВОБОДА
Barnes &amp;amp; Noble Organizing Book Clubs at all their Stores
Ebook Accessibility: Here’s What You Might Be Missing – EPUBSecrets</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Некоторые полезные ссылки ссылки февраля 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-03-08-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 11:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-03-08-a/</guid>
      <description>In Defence of Fixed-Layout Ebooks – EPUBSecrets
100 магазинов за год – рекорд на книжном рынке
Издатели заработали на детях – Газета Коммерсантъ № 19 (6257) от 02.02.2018
A flurry of activity in the long-stagnant e-book market » MobyLives
Piracy Can Help Music Sales of Many Artists, Research Shows - TorrentFreak
Updated: Scribd App Update Reveals Return of Unlimited(*) Reading | The Digital Reader Ну, то есть не совсем unlimited. По некоторым книгам будет лимит, про который узнают только те, кто на него наткнутся.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Полезные ссылки января 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-02-05-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 12:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-02-05-a/</guid>
      <description>Barnes &amp;amp; Noble Reports Holiday Revenues Down 6.4% | The Digital Reader
Sales of Print Books Increased, Slightly, in 2017
First Public Working Drafts: Web Publications, Packaged Web Publications, and Web Annotation Extensions for Web Publications | W3C News Анонс публикации первого черновика спецификаций Web Publications, Packaged Web Publications и Web Annotation Extensions for Web Publications.
App replaces Twitter with Kindle / Boing Boing Хорошая идея. Вместо того, чтобы в Твиттере сидеть, книжки идите читать.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Небесполезные ссылки декабря 2017</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-01-06-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 18:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-01-06-a/</guid>
      <description>«Массового читателя больше нет». Подводим итоги книжного года вместе с участниками ярмарки Non/fiction в ЦДХ
Ъ: «Просвещение» сдало «Экзамен»
Как группа предпринимателей поставила на поток производство сомнительных учебников: Деловой климат: Экономика: Lenta.ru Две статьи про ещё одну историю о жабе и гадюке в книжной индустрии. Особенно той её части, где крутятся государственные деньги.
Project Alexandria - Helping you find your next favorite book
Ten Years Ago Amazon Started A Revolution and It Just Gave Me a Very Good Month | The Idea Logical Company Майк Шацкин отмечает юбилей Kindle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ссылки ноября 2017</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-12-11-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 09:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-12-11-a/</guid>
      <description>В ноябре было много всяких новостей. Отдельным блоком в конце — ссылки на материалы конференции W3Publishing и, отдельно, на разные workflow для производства EPUB.
Redmadrobot выписался из библиотеки – Газета Коммерсантъ № 203 (6197) от 31.10.2017
Kindle Create (Beta) | Amazon Kindle Direct Publishing
Audible Launches an &amp;ldquo;All-You-Can-Listen&amp;rdquo; Romance Service | The Digital Reader
Audible Romance is a New Unlimited Subscription Service
Шведский литературный социализм
DRM-free E-Bookshops
Amazon Kindle Lite for Android is a New App for Indian Readers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ссылки октября</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-11-13-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 09:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-11-13-a/</guid>
      <description>Marcel Proust paid for reviews praising his work to go into newspapers | Books | The Guardian О том, как Пруст платил за рецензии на свои книги.
People Are Weird About Books, and Attempts to &amp;ldquo;Improve&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Fix&amp;rdquo; Books in a Web Browser Prove it | The Digital Reader
E-books in academic libraries: results of a survey carried out in Sweden and Lithuania
Distribution Expansion: Germany&amp;rsquo;s Bookwire Acquires Brazil&amp;rsquo;s DLD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ссылки августа 2017</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-09-03-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 11:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-09-03-a/</guid>
      <description>Digital isn&amp;rsquo;t dead for book publishers - we&amp;rsquo;re just waking up from the first hangover | The Bookseller
Less Than Meets the Eye: Print Book Use Is Falling Faster in Research Libraries - The Scholarly Kitchen Бумажные книги в библиотеках исследовательских центров США всё меньше востребованы. Что и понятно.
China and the US release 48% of the world’s books (chart) Последний отчет IPA 2015-2016 полностью игнорирует Россию. Удивительно.
Canadians are starting to read more books on their smartphones Что не очень удивительно — повсеместный тренд.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Линки июня 2107</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-07-04-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 13:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-07-04-a/</guid>
      <description>Semantic HTML5 as She is Wrote: An Exploration of i, em, b, and strong – EPUBSecrets
Online regex tester and debugger: PHP, PCRE, Python, Golang and JavaScript
JellyBooks Shuts Down Its eBook Discovery Service | The Digital Reader
Building books with Markdown using pandoc – Programmers — Developers – Medium
Here is an observation from our experience at Jellybooks Ltd.
Книжный рынок Великобритании: возможность выбора как фактор успеха
Москвичи забрали из библиотек более 130 тысяч старых книг — Российская газета</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ссылки за май 2017</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-06-04-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 18:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-06-04-a/</guid>
      <description>Japan e-book distributor Media Do to build &amp;lsquo;AI translator&amp;rsquo;- Nikkei Asian Review
Audible Creates $5 Million Fund for Emerging Playwrights - The New York Times
Go To Hellman: Readium&amp;rsquo;s New Licensed Content Protection May Result in Better Reader Privacy
Amazon Just Invented Borders Books – 500ish Words
First impressions of an Amazon bookstore - The Idea Logical Company
Dosdoce and Bookwire Chart &amp;lsquo;Soaring&amp;rsquo; Ebook Sales in Spanish Markets
Медиапотребление в России – 2017 | | «Делойт», СНГ | Высокие технологии, телекоммуникации, развлечения и СМИ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ссылки апрель 2017</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-05-02-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 07:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-05-02-a/</guid>
      <description>LINKS 2017-04 Macmillan Publishers · GitHub
На МЦК открылась бесплатная «Мобильная библиотека»
Tech Forum 2017 - BookNet Canada
BookNet Canada presentations channel
Past Tech Forum events « Tech Forum &amp;amp; ebookcraft: Canada&amp;rsquo;s largest tech-focused conference for the book industry
eBookcraft Conference Presentation Videos Now Online | The Digital Reader
Damn the Facts: The &amp;ldquo;Ebook Sales Are Down&amp;rdquo; Narrative Must be Maintained at All Costs | The Digital Reader
Fancy Free: Some Fun CSS Tricks for Ebooks - The Book Designer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Линки за март (2017)</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-04-02-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 18:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-04-02-a/</guid>
      <description>OZON.ru подвел итоги 2016 года
30 Best Self-Publishing Tools and Resources for Your Next Book
Germany&amp;rsquo;s Latest &amp;lsquo;KIM-Studie&amp;rsquo;: Children&amp;rsquo;s Media Usage Is Mobile and Busy
Creating a Book Cover Using JavaScript and p5.js | CSS-Tricks
Open Textbook Library
Lithuanians and Their Books: Highly Literate Readers, Fond of Translations
The Myth About Print Coming Back (Updated) | Jane Friedman
Third of EU Citizens OK With Piracy When There Are No Legal Options - TorrentFreak</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ссылки февраля 2017</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-03-05-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 18:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-03-05-a/</guid>
      <description>Mozilla acquires Pocket to gain a foothold on mobile devices - The Verge
Making books with HTML CSS — a look at Vivliostyle (Part 1 – page layouts) – Paged Media
Where are the Page Up and Page Down Keys on my Laptop?
Состоялось заседание Правления Российского книжного союза
Annotation is now a web standard – Hypothesis
Paul Biba’s eBook, eLibrary, eMuseum and ePublishing news compilation for week ending Saturday, February 25 | The Digital Reader</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Линки января</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-02-03-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 08:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-02-03-a/</guid>
      <description>Kindle for PC gains text-to-speech (but makes stripping DRM harder) - Liliputing
Shelfie to Shutdown on 31 January - Download Your eBooks NOW | The Digital Reader
New Kindle Publishing Guidelines Swaps References to &amp;ldquo;E-ink&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;e-Reader&amp;rdquo; | The Digital Reader
BookNet Canada Reports Print, eBook Sales Down in 2016 | The Digital Reader
Canadian publishing in 2016: A review — BookNet Canada
PayPal Has Been Talking With Amazon on Payments, CEO Says - Bloomberg</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Кое-какие ссылки первой недели января</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-01-08-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 18:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-01-08-a/</guid>
      <description>Members Unanimously Approve EPUB 3.1 as an IDPF Recommended Specification | International Digital Publishing Forum
Making a Book from Scratch is More Work Than You Think (video) | The Digital Reader
Kobo becomes new technology partner at the tolino alliance | Kobo Newsroom
Barnes and Noble Nook Losses Continue to Mount
The 2017 State of Self-Publishing
Insert a Character by Unicode or GID - InDesignSecrets : InDesignSecrets
Personanondata: Predictions 2017: Subscribe To Me</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Любопытные ссылки 12–18 декабря 2016</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-12-20-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 12:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-12-20-a/</guid>
      <description>Проект Open eBooks (электронные книги для детей из малообеспеченных семей) отчитался о своей работе
60 немецких университетов с 1 января послали Elsevier
Фонд выплат авторам книг Kindle Unlimited в ноябре 2016 Amazon немного поднял — до $16,3 млн
Подъём, ага (сарказм): October Bookstore Sales Slipped 1%
Что читатели электронных книг, независимые издатели и библиотеки должны потребовать у IDPF перед слиянием с W3C
Internet Archive продолжает готовиться к худшему при президенте Трампе: Preserving U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Разные любопытные ссылки 14–20/20/2016</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-11-22-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 21:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-11-22-a/</guid>
      <description>Пошли аудиокнигу в подарок: Audible &amp;ldquo;Send this Book&amp;rdquo; Launches in Germany, and Maybe the UK and France | The Digital Reader
Overdrive Launches New Library Websites and App - Digital Book World
Amazon тестирует подарочные открытки для конкретных книг Amazon Ends Pilot Test of Title-Specific Kindle Gift Cards | The Digital Reader (а у нас уже есть Book-in-card)
Inkitt Announces Global Launch of iOS App - Digital Book World
The books have never been more exciting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Любопытные ссылки прошлой недели (7–13 ноября 2016)</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-11-14-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 08:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-11-14-a/</guid>
      <description>Две статьи, посвященные анализу чтения в сервисе Букмейт: Large-Scale Log Analysis of Digital Reading
Ten Months of Digital Reading: An Exploratory Log Study
Books in Browsers: Visualization and &amp;lsquo;Responsible Data&amp;rsquo;
Подписочный сервис из Польши выходит в Германию
HarperCollins eBook Revenues Fell in 1st Fiscal Quarter 2017 | The Digital Reader
Kindle Unlimited Launches in Australia at a Pricy $14 a Month | The Digital Reader
Books-a-Million Partners With FastPencil (Again), Now Sells Space on its Shelves | The Digital Reader</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Вчерашние закладки 2016–11–01</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-11-01-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 06:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-11-01-a/</guid>
      <description>‘Europeana for Research’ - digitisation, copyright reform and advocacy beyond the pilot stage - Europeana Professional
Michael Tamblyn of Kobo presents What No One Tells You About Growing an International Business - YouTube
The Future of Libraries | Massachusetts Institute of Technology
Why People Joined the Beta Reading Team – Writing Novels – Medium
The UK is Adopting Audiobooks at about the Same Rate as the US | The Digital Reader</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindle Page Flip — новая навигация электронных книг</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-06-28-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 13:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-06-28-a/</guid>
      <description>   Радикальное обновление навигации на Kindle — теперь электронные книги можно и правда перелистывать. А не только листать страницу за страницей, как раньше. Amazon, конечно, пошёл по более простому пути, чем старые эксперименты (см. ниже), но тоже хорошо.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Пара ссылок на заметку</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-11-29-137/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 22:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-11-29-137/</guid>
      <description>Secret Agent Librarian
Welcome to Web Books Publishing
P. S. Archive</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
