<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ebooks on Новости электронного книгоиздания</title>
    <link>/tags/ebooks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ebooks on Новости электронного книгоиздания</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 10:31:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ebooks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Гузель Яхина об электронных книгах</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-01-10-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 10:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-01-10-a/</guid>
      <description>Электронный формат беспощаден. Он предъявляет к автору самые высокие требования. В цифровой книге автор остается с читателем один на один. Между ними – лишь текст, и все его изъяны и недостатки видны крайне отчетливо. Затянутость, беспомощность сюжета, рыхлая структура, скудный слог – экран высвечивает слабости, как рентген. Не спрятаться за впечатляющей суперобложкой, за внутренним дизайном, за запахом качественной бумаги, за сложенным веками авторитетом печатного слова. Текст и читатель – тет-а-тет, на бескрайних и пустынных просторах цифрового формата.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Хороший повод съездить в Париж</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-02-25-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 12:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-02-25-a/</guid>
      <description>Музей цифровых книг на улице Сен-Медар, 2.
 Source: E-book museum will open in Paris: How about a U.S. one, too? - TeleRead News: E-books, publishing, tech and beyond
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ура! Books in Browsers VII</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-02-19-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 21:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-02-19-a/</guid>
      <description>http://booksinbrowsers.org/submit-your-proposal-vii/ Конференция Интернет-архива &amp;ldquo;Книги в браузерах&amp;rdquo; опять будет. 3-4 ноября 2016 в Сан-Франциско. Про короткие истории, не только книжные. Очень рекомендую.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Проект Gutenberg. 50 тысяч книг</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-10-06-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 09:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-10-06-a/</guid>
      <description>Project Gutenberg is thrilled to achieve the milestone of eBook #50,000. In honor of Project Gutenberg&amp;rsquo;s founder, Michael S. Hart, a special title was selected. &amp;ldquo;John Gutenberg, First Master Printer, His Acts, and most remarkable Discourses, and his Death&amp;rdquo; is now available at www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/50000. Johannes (or John) Gutenberg is best known for introducing mechanical movable type printing to Europe. This brought about a revolution in printing, which was a key event in shaping today&amp;rsquo;s information and knowlege-based society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Гуманитарии обратили внимание на цифровые книги: Alessandro Ludovico: Post-Digital Print – The Mutation of Publishing Since 1894 (2012)</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-05-20-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 23:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-05-20-a/</guid>
      <description>via monoskop.org
Must read. Ну, за отсутствием пока выбора.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant publishing есть и в России</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-09-20-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 19:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-09-20-1/</guid>
      <description>FastBook — это книга, которая пытается рассказать большую историю, основанную на событиях сегодняшнего дня. FastBook — это книга, которая распространяется только в цифровом формате. FastBook — это книга, которая описывает реальные события нашей жизни вскоре после того, как они произошли, а не спустя полтора года (потому что не связана с неповоротливой печатью). FastBook — это книга, которая читается быстро, потому что она длиннее самой длинной журнальной статьи, но короче обычной книги, которая пишется подлиннее зачастую только для того, чтобы заполнить страницы.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Теории и практике&#34; на заметку</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-07-12-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 14:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-07-12-6/</guid>
      <description>The success of TEDTalks has demonstrated that millions of people around the world are hungry to absorb new ideas. Many of the talks create a desire to go deeper &amp;ndash; but not everyone has the time to read an entire book on a subject. TED Books fill that gap. While a traditional book is at least 60,000 words, TED Books, at less than 20,000, allow someone to see an idea fleshed out in a satisfying way &amp;ndash; but without having to devote a week of reading time to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quakebook - оч. правильный проект</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-04-21-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-04-21-b/</guid>
      <description>Quakebook
ON SALE NOW!!
In just four weeks, the 2:46 Quakebook project turned an idea first voiced in a single tweet, into a rich collection of essays, artwork and photographs submitted by indivdiuals around the world, including people who endured the disaster and journalists who covered it.
2:46: Aftershocks: Stories from the Japan Earthquake contains a piece by Yoko Ono, and work created specifically for the book by authors William Gibson, Barry Eisler and Jake Adelstein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Электронная книга и свиток</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-04-17-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 08:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-04-17-a/</guid>
      <description>Пришло в голову после эссе Кевина Келли «Чем станут книги»: электронные книги отчасти вернутся к свиткам — пагинация бессмысленна, а вот маркирование абзацев будет актуально — для ссылок и гиперссылок.
А текст Келли надо бы перевести.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Кто станет издателем?</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-04-11-e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 09:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-04-11-e/</guid>
      <description>The AAA constitution says anyone employed by a publisher should not be eligible for membership. Piers Blofeld of Sheil Land said the AAA should reflect the &amp;ldquo;fast-changing landscape&amp;rdquo; of publishing. He said: &amp;ldquo;There are obvious issues and potential conflicts of interest, but at heart the role of an agent is to offer advice and support to a writer on their writing career. We&amp;rsquo;re here to maximise their earnings. We&amp;rsquo;re not simply there to act as an interface between authors and publishers—that landscape has gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Денис Драгунский об электронных книгах</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-04-06-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 11:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-04-06-a/</guid>
      <description>Наверное, в своё время кому-то милее были глиняные таблички. С ними было гораздо приятнее, чем с папирусом, сидеть в тени зиккурата.
 via chaskor.ru
Существенные вещи о чтении и — шире — обращении с книгой.
Правда, это только обещанное начало. Ждем продолжения.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>К вопросу об электронных книгах и бумажных</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-03-31-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 16:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-03-31-a/</guid>
      <description>Баян, конечно. Но актуальный ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Шацкин: эл.книги – это дешевый массмаркет XXI века</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-03-21-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 20:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-03-21-c/</guid>
      <description>The ebook revolution is really beginning to remind me of the mass-market papeback revolution.
 Весьма познавательная история «книжек в обложках».</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Неделя электронной книги, между прочим</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-03-09-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 12:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-03-09-2/</guid>
      <description>via ebookweek.com
Понятно, что это маркетинг. Но симпатичный. Кстати, в этом году действительно 40 лет электронным книгам: в июле 1971 года Мартин Харт самолично набил &amp;ldquo;Декларацию независимости США&amp;rdquo;. Так начался Проект &amp;ldquo;Гутенберг&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Пропустил: 13 февраля New York Times начал печатать списки ebook-бестселлеров</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-03-05-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 12:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-03-05-a/</guid>
      <description>1 UNBROKEN, by Laura Hillenbrand. (Random House.) An Olympic runner’s story of survival as a prisoner of the Japanese in World War II. 1
Sunday Book Review | Books of The Times Review
2 HEAVEN IS FOR REAL, by Todd Burpo with Lynn Vincent. (Thomas Nelson.) A father recounts his 3-year-old son’s encounter with Jesus and the angels during an emergency appendectomy. 1
3 BATTLE HYMN OF THE TIGER MOTHER, by Amy Chua.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Сервис сканирования книг</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-02-08-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 12:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-02-08-b/</guid>
      <description>via wired.com
Интересно, а в России такое сервис есть? И почему нет? Доллар за книжку — совсем не дорого. Я бы с удовольствием заказал оцифровку своей библиотеки. Пока можно.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flat World Knowledge - интересная бизнес-модель</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-01-20-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 21:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-01-20-d/</guid>
      <description>We preserve the best of the old — books by leading experts, peer‑reviewed and developed to high editorial standards, fully supported by review copies, teaching supplements and great service. Then we change everything. Our textbooks are:
 Free online Affordable offline Open–licensed Customizable by educators  Educators choose the book — students choose format and price. Everybody wins.
 via flatworldknowledge.com
Учебники онлайн - бесплатно. Скачать, купить в бумаге и т.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journal of Electronic Publishing: Welcome</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-01-12-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 22:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-01-12-c/</guid>
      <description>via journalofelectronicpublishing.org
Всегда догадывался, что у англосаксов должен быть журнал на любую тему. Но на журнал про электронное издательство наткнулся только что. Градиска!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Новый мир&#34; для букридеров</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-01-07-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 23:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-01-07-a/</guid>
      <description>via avvas.livejournal.com
Молодцы.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>В списках бестселлеров New York Times появятся электронные книги</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-11-11-217/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 08:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-11-11-217/</guid>
      <description>In an acknowledgment of the growing sales and influence of digital publishing, The New York Times said on Wednesday that it would publish e-book best-seller lists in fiction and nonfiction beginning early next year.
 via nytimes.com
Типа - свершилось. Шатцкин, кстати, резко критикует последний отчёт Forrester, и говорит, что $1 млрд — крайне заниженная оценка, поскольку методология хромает, не учитывая читателей электронных книг на компах.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Платформа для цифровой публикации Adobe будет сервисом</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-10-25-148/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 10:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-10-25-148/</guid>
      <description>Pricing for the Professional Edition is expected to be $699 per month plus a per-issue fee that scales according to volume. For that price, publishers can access the Digital Publishing Suite and create applications for all of their titles and publications. The Enterprise Edition is a custom, multi-year platform agreement that gives publishers access to technologies for integration of back-end services such as subscription management, print fulfillment, and e-commerce. Adobe also offers professional services to support enterprise level projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhook - формат электронных книг</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-10-15-237/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 08:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-10-15-237/</guid>
      <description>via ochook.org
Чего только не бывает, вот, например, ещё один формат ебуков — Жук, сорри, Zhook. Что-то типа EPUB, но только в одном зазипованном файле в HTML5. Последнее обстоятельство как раз очень перспективно. Но, думаю, EPUB тоже будет туда двигаться.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Началась каннибализация? Или электронные книги - это другой рынок?</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-09-23-117/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 15:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-09-23-117/</guid>
      <description>The data, released as part of a seminar held yesterday with Enders Analysis, &amp;lsquo;Digital Seminar: e-books and their impact on the market&amp;rsquo;, showed genres such as science fiction and romance are “overperforming” thanks to the tastes of early adopters of e-books. For example, the e-book market share of the science fiction and fantasy sector globally for the 10 weeks since June was 10%, more than treble the genre’s market share of print book sales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blio запустят 28 сентября</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-09-23-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 14:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-09-23-30/</guid>
      <description>K-NFB Reading Technology, creator and developer of Blio, today announced that the world’s most advanced, flexible and engaging e-reader application, will be available for download beginning September 28 at www.blioreader.com. Blio, which is free to download, will be available immediately for all Windows-based devices, with applications for iOS and Android operating systems following soon after. In the coming months, Blio will be rolled out worldwide through device manufacturers, retailers, mobile carriers and educational institutions, and supported by fully-customized digital media storefronts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Книжка для глухих детей на iPad</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-09-13-96/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 21:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-09-13-96/</guid>
      <description>Оч. уважаю. Молодцы прямо.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Covers - Tools of Change for Publishing</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-08-06-134/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 14:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-08-06-134/</guid>
      <description>via toc.oreilly.com
Отличные обложки для ебуков.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lonely Planet выпустило путеводители с расширенной реальностью</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-08-04-109/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 14:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-08-04-109/</guid>
      <description>Lonely Planet has launched augmented reality guides for UK&amp;rsquo;s Google Android users.
Its &amp;lsquo;Compass Guides&amp;rsquo; are available for 25 locations including Amsterdam, Bangkok, Barcelona, Hong Kong, Istanbul, London, Paris, Prague and New York City. They are available for $4.99 (£3.12) from the Google Android store.
Matthew Cashmore, innovation and ecosystems manager, said: &amp;ldquo;This is one of the most innovative things we’ve launched and we’re really excited to see how people use this application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>А вот и видео про Adobe Content Builder</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-07-19-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 18:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-07-19-6/</guid>
      <description>via tv.adobe.com
Начало стандартизации «фишек».</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quark --&gt; Blio</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-06-20-174/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 09:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-06-20-174/</guid>
      <description>via mobilitysite.com
Как интересно. Quark пробует выжить за счёт превращения в инструмент для создания электронных материалов для новой платформы Blio, которую готовит Рэй Курцвейль. Проблема только в том, что Blio ещё нет и её будущее, учитывая заполненность рынка, непонятна.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geo-aware ebook demo : Threepress Consulting blog</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-06-10-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 19:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-06-10-71/</guid>
      <description>via blog.threepress.org
Пример страницы электронной книги (webkit-based), определяющей ваше местоположение.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing the digital book — Craig Mod</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-04-23-63/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 22:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-04-23-63/</guid>
      <description>via craigmod.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books in the Age of the iPad — Craig Mod</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-03-07-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2010 14:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-03-07-34/</guid>
      <description>via craigmod.com
Точка зрения дизайнера. Весьма взвешенная и позитивная.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Полезная статья о фальстарте электронных книг в начале века</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-02-25-155/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 22:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-02-25-155/</guid>
      <description>via publishingtrends.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Проект бесплатного электронного издательства в Египте</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-23-125/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-23-125/</guid>
      <description>Marwa Rakha’s free e-publishing does not censor and does not have any guidelines for manuscript acceptance whatsoever.
Rakha says that “if you think you are a writer, if you think you want people to hear your voice, if you do not want to be at the mercy of a publisher who will make you pay, will not print the number of copies he promised, will not distribute the book properly, and will not market the book or author, then… you have a home with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aptara запустила eGen</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-11-19-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 13:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-11-19-18/</guid>
      <description>The eGen Platform
 The eGen platform is the only technology to automatically generate large volumes of high-quality eBook-ready content at a dramatically reduced cost. This offers publishers a truly flexible solution for distributing their content to eReaders including the Amazon Kindle, SONY Reader, Apple iPhone, and a variety of new devices, such as Barnes &amp;amp; Noble’s Nook.
Convert your content assets for a multitude of eReaders with eGen and benefit from:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O&#39;Reilly берет на себя Microsoft Press</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-09-24-110/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2009 20:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-09-24-110/</guid>
      <description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media and Microsoft Announce Plans to Expand Microsoft Press: O&amp;rsquo;Reilly to Distribute Microsoft Press Titles and Launch New Ebook Initiatives
 O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media, Inc. and Microsoft Corp. today announced a joint arrangement to support and expand Microsoft Press from production through distribution, co-publishing and content development, marketing and management. Through this strategic relationship, on November 30, O&amp;rsquo;Reilly will become the distributor of Microsoft Press titles in North America with a global roll out in a phased approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 млн экз книжки Брауна продано за неделю. 5% - в электронном виде</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-09-22-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2009 21:24:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-09-22-33/</guid>
      <description>New Dan Brown novel tops 2 million mark - Yahoo! Finance
 Doubleday announced Tuesday that hardcover, audio and e-book sales for &amp;ldquo;The Lost Symbol&amp;rdquo; topped 2 million copies for its first week of release in the United States, Britain and Canada. The total is &amp;ldquo;well over&amp;rdquo; 2 million for English-language editions worldwide, according to Doubleday spokeswoman Suzanne Herz, who declined to offer a specific number. Herz did say that around 5 percent, or 100,000 copies, of &amp;ldquo;The Lost Symbol&amp;rdquo; were sold as e-books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Продажи последней книги Дэна Брауна для Kindle на Amazon превысили продажи бумажной версии</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-09-16-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 21:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-09-16-32/</guid>
      <description>Kindle Nation Daily: Kindle edition of The Lost Symbol outselling Amazon hardcovers!
 As of 10:30 a.m. EDT today, September 15, the Kindle edition is ahead of the hardcover edition in Amazon&amp;rsquo;s own hourly-updated sales rankings.
 Может быть, это и не надолго. И, конечно, это только относительные данные продаж самого Amazon. Но факт исключительно примечательный.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Издаельство Мичиганского университета переходит на выпуск электронных книг</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-03-23-76/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 22:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-03-23-76/</guid>
      <description>University of Michigan Press to go digital | TeleRead: Bring the E-Books Home
 Within two years, press officials expect well over 50 of the 60-plus monographs that the press publishes each year — currently in book form — to be released only in digital editions. Readers will still be able to use print-on-demand systems to produce versions that can be held in their hands, but the press will consider the digital monograph the norm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
