<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ereaders on Новости электронного книгоиздания</title>
    <link>/tags/ereaders/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ereaders on Новости электронного книгоиздания</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 10:48:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ereaders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>R.I.P. Sony Reader (2004–2014)</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-08-14-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 10:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-08-14-a/</guid>
      <description>Пишут, что Sony прекращает выпуск читалок на eInk. Совсем. Даже для японского рынка. Компания, с которой, собственно, начался полноценный рынок электронных книг (первая читалка на eInk — Sony Librie появилась в 2004), уходит с него совсем. Может, это и логично: это совсем не рынок гаджетов (казалось десять лет назад), и электронная книга — это не букридер. Точнее, не столько букридер, сколько магазин, ассортимент, доступность и пр.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Смартфон-букридер для техноненавистников</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-06-25-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 13:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-06-25-b/</guid>
      <description>Компания Onyx, производитель не самых плохих eInk-букридеров давно обещала, и вот объявила о начале поставок в Европу смартфона Midia InkPhone. Сам смартфон «старенький» — Android 2.3.5, никакого 3G. Экран 4.3 дюйма. Но этот экран — eInk Mobius (16 градаций серого, подсветка). Соответственно, обещанный срок работы на одной зарядке — 2 недели. И читать удобнее ) Цена на предзаказе (до 4 июля) — 149 €. С доставкой в Россию — 152 €.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Последний букридер? Kobo Aura HD</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-04-16-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 12:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-04-16-a/</guid>
      <description>Kobo Aura HD offers the highest-resolution screen available in an eReader today. At 265 dpi, the spacious 6.8” Pearl E Ink touchscreen offers 30 percent more reading surface and the closest experience to print-on-paper – showcasing text and high-resolution images beautifully. The device’s 1GHz processor makes page turns fly and is the fastest eReader on the market – 25 percent faster. Kobo Aura HD has 4GB of storage (expandable up to 32GB) to easily store thousands of eBooks, and has a battery life of up to two months, making it the perfect eReader for people with a passion for the written word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Новый NOOK Simple Touch с хитрой подсвткой GlowLight</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-04-12-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 20:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-04-12-b/</guid>
      <description>via barnesandnoble.com
Про новый Kindle с такой подсветкой (как я понимаю, не просто светодиоды, а сам экран как-то хитро светится) только слухи появились, а B&amp;amp;N уже предлагает предзаказ делать. Выглядит оч. симпатично.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E Ink выручила $1 млрд в 2011 году</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-11-11-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 07:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-11-11-b/</guid>
      <description>E Ink Holdings announced today that the company&amp;rsquo;s 2011 revenues reached NT$ 33.271 billion from January to October - crossing the $1 billion mark.
E Ink&amp;rsquo;s revenue climbed 83% compared to last year, mostly due to increased sales of e-reader products.
 via e-ink-info.com
Выручка компании выросла за год на 83%.
Что не удивительно: 6-дюймовый экранчик Pearl стоит 30 баксов.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony Reader T1 взломали и поставили на него Kindle</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-10-24-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 09:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-10-24-3/</guid>
      <description>Правильно ли я понимаю, что T1 работает втихаря работает на Android? Или просто умудрились на него поставить?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WEXLER с гибким экраном</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-10-19-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 18:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-10-19-5/</guid>
      <description>via wexler.ru
Экранчик от РОСНАНО, что ли? Но забавно.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Статистика использования букридеров в США</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-09-21-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 11:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-09-21-2/</guid>
      <description>The Harris Poll also revealed one in six Americans who do not have an e-reader intend to buy one during the next six months. This may be welcomed by publishers as e-reader owners are reading more books, according to the survey. Overall, 16% of Americans read between 11 and 20 books per year with 20% reading more than 21. However, a third of those who own a Kindle, Nook or other device read 11-20 books a year with 27% reading more than 21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Чубайсу на заметку: финны помогут китайцам наладить текстовещание</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-09-15-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 14:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-09-15-2/</guid>
      <description>The Helsinki Metropolia University of Applied Sciences, Aalto University and the National Engineering Center of Digital Television (NERC-DTV) plan to make a low-power, reception only device based on an E-ink screen. The screen and general hardware design are expected to cheap and require minimal power, and that should make it possible to power the e-reader completely from a solar panel.
 via the-digital-reader.com
На устройства с «электронными чернилами». Видимо, китайских государственных новостей.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony так-таки открывает книжный магазин для Европы</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-09-05-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 13:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-09-05-1/</guid>
      <description>Reader Store first rolled out in North America back in 2006 and in Sony’s native Japan in 2010.
Now a UK launch is planned for October 2011, with Germany and Austria planned by year’s end and France, Italy and Spain early in 2012. Further new markets are also on the cards.
The launch dovetails with the WiFi-enabled new Reader e-reader Sony announced at IFA in Berlin, which has a touch-screen and pinch-zoom text resizing and is lighter than Kindle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Пользователи читалок — пожилые женщины (Nielsen, USA)</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-08-25-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 13:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-08-25-2/</guid>
      <description>Любопытное развитие рынка: менее, чем за год пользователи читалок в США сильно повзрослели - 51% старше 45 лет (30% старше 55), причём 9 месяцев назад старше 45-ти лет было 40% (25% старше 55). Та же тенденция с пользователями планшетников: 37% старше 45 (19% старше 55), а три квартала назад — 23% старше 45-ти (10% ещё старше).
Половая структура тоже поменялась — в III кв 2010 букридеры были по преимуществу у мужчин (54%), теперь — у женщин (61%).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Читалка Чубайса может оказаться вполне ничего себе</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-08-24-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 09:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-08-24-1/</guid>
      <description>Но только не за 400 баксов.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ритейлеры о ридерах</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-08-15-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 14:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-08-15-2/</guid>
      <description>За полгода с января по июнь 2011 г. «Евросеть» продала в 14,8 раза больше ридеров, чем за аналогичный период прошлого года (+1379%), рассказала представитель торговой сети Ульяна Смольская. За семь месяцев 2011 г. ритейлер продал ридеров больше, чем за весь 2010 год, добавляет она. В денежном выражении продажи этих устройств выросли в первом полугодии 2011 г. к тому же периоду 2010 г. в 5 раз (+410%).
 via vedomosti.ru</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Китайский главный поисковик Baidu купил производителя букридеров. Яндекс! Ау!</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-08-05-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 10:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-08-05-3/</guid>
      <description>Baidu, China’s home-grown version of Google, now own about 40% of Fan Shu, maker of the Yambook ebook reader.
 via the-digital-reader.com
После скандала с «пиратством» на книжном сервисе Baidu поисковик договорился со крупными китайскими издателями. А теперь вот и поисковик купил. Логично.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Букридер для школ Украины</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-08-05-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 09:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-08-05-1/</guid>
      <description>Компания AirOn, занимающаяся разработкой и поставкой на украинский рынок букридеров под торговой маркой AirBook Liber, намеревается поставлять электронные учебники для школьников 5-12 классов и студентов 1-2 курсов украинских вузов.
Пресс-служба компании объявила о создании букридера, содержащего учебный материал по всем предметным направлениям для указанных категорий учащихся. Сообщается, что контент электронного учебника полностью соответствует методическим рекомендациям Минобразования Украины и включает не только текстовые материалы, но и графику, аудиозаписи и словари.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Прототип цветного дисплея для букридера Fujitsu</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-07-13-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 10:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-07-13-1/</guid>
      <description>via teleread.com
4096 цветов, 8-дюймовый дисплей (157 ppi), 0,7 секунд на обновление экрана. 220 грамм. ОК.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking, тассазать, news: интегрированный с Google eBooks букридер</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-07-11-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 14:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-07-11-a/</guid>
      <description>via googleblog.blogspot.com
В буридер iriver Story HD ($140 в США) будет устанавливаться программа для доступа к Google eBooks (подключение к сети через WiFi). Это, конечно, не альтернатива Kindle. Но решение Google не сбрасывать со счетов букридеры оч. правильное.
Для России, конечно, не акутально, поскольку Google eBooks здесь работает весьма ограничено, но интересная тенденция.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Японские производители читалок готовятся к обороне</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-06-15-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 20:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-06-15-b/</guid>
      <description>Четыре японских производителя Sony, Panasonic, Rakuten и Kinokuniya, занимающихся продажей электронных книг, объединили свои усилия в этой области. На днях четвёрка сообщила о том, что ею ведутся работы над универсальной системой, которая позволит приобретать и читать контент на ридерах любой из четырёх компаний.
В рамках новой службы потребители получат централизованную возможность управления своими закачками и просмотра магазина электронных книг, независимо от того, устройство какой из четырёх японских компаний они предпочитают.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Операционная система исламской электронной книги eAlim EL1000</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-06-14-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 13:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-06-14-c/</guid>
      <description>Operating System Core: ENMAC Islamic Software
 via store.dar-us-salam.com
Вот и киберислам.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Веб-скроллинг в букридере</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-05-21-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 11:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-05-21-b/</guid>
      <description>Новые Cybook будут, видимо, вполне подходить для просмотра черно-белого кино.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony показала 13-дюймовый гибкий цветной комбинированный дисплей</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-05-20-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 10:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-05-20-c/</guid>
      <description>via techon.nikkeibp.co.jp
Слой чернил + слой специально приготовленных ЖК.
Разрешение, правда, 150 ppi.
P. S. Archive</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Читалка Kobo за $99,98</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-05-12-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 09:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-05-12-b/</guid>
      <description>via walmart.com
Такие ценовые войны - аж завидно.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Дальше нас ждут гибкие смартфоны?</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-05-11-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 20:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-05-11-a/</guid>
      <description>via bits.blogs.nytimes.com
Пока выглядит диковато. У нынешнего букридера хоть какой-то вес есть. А если представить себе такую читалку — то как-то стрёмно: огрызок пластика…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worldreader - программа распространения букридеров в африканских школах</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-04-02-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 14:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-04-02-b/</guid>
      <description>До российских школ, видимо, хрен доберется.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Объем российского рынка букридеров в 2010 году составил 539000 штук | Pro-Books.ru</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-03-05-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 08:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-03-05-c/</guid>
      <description>По итогам 2010 года общий объем продаж устройств для чтения цифровых книг на российском рынке оказался значительно больше, нежели указывалось в предварительных данных, и составил 539000 штук (с учетом ридеров с дисплеем на основе технологии «электронных чернил», а также «псевдоридеров» – устройств с TFT-дисплеем). Годовой рост рынка, таким образом, составил 285%.
 via pro-books.ru
То есть весь рынок букридеров можно оценить по меньшей мере в 700-800 тыс. Скромно.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 фунтов = 1414 рублей</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-02-24-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 09:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-02-24-a/</guid>
      <description>via mediabistro.com
Видимо, самый дешёвый букридер в Великобритании.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Букридер Alex - всё?</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-02-24-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 08:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-02-24-b/</guid>
      <description>Topical items and views on the impact of digitisation on publishing and its content and the issues that make the news. This blog follows the report &amp;lsquo;Brave New World&amp;rsquo;, (http://www.ewidgetsonline.com/vcil/bravenewworld.html ), published by the Booksellers Association of the UK and Ireland and authored by Martyn Daniels. The views and comments expressed are those of the author.
 via bookseller-association.blogspot.com
Конкуренция на рынке становится смертельной. Plastic Logic от банкротства в прошлом году спас Чубайс и «Роснано», но будет ли он делать букридеры, неизвестно.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color E-Readers Open Way for Picture Books - NYTimes.com</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-12-15-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 09:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-12-15-42/</guid>
      <description>Apple said Tuesday that it was set to make a major push into illustrated books on Wednesday, introducing more than 100 titles to its iBookstore, an assortment of children’s books, photography books and cookbooks.
Some of the most popular children’s picture books of all time will be available, including some of the “Olivia” picture books, published by Simon &amp;amp; Schuster. Other titles are “Ad Hoc at Home,” a lavish cookbook by the chef Thomas Keller; “Beginnings,” by the photographer Anne Geddes; and “In the National Parks,” a photograph collection by Ansel Adams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Роснано так-таки инвестирует в Plastic Logic</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-11-09-178/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 23:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-11-09-178/</guid>
      <description>Moscow and Mountain View, California – November 9, 2010 – Russian Corporation of Nanotechnologies and Plastic Logic Inc. today announced they have entered into an agreement to create Plastic Logic’s second volume production facility for its next-generation plastic electronic displays and establish a plastic electronics industry in Russia. Under the terms of agreement RUSNANO intends to make a significant investment in the company, which is the global leader in the emerging field of plastic electronics, as part of a large-scale investment project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Айчиталка-таки в продаже</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-09-23-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 15:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-09-23-9/</guid>
      <description>Всего за 6499 руб. включая доставку по Москве
 imobilco.ru
Правда, не за 5999, а за 6499 рублей. Если не смущает чуть меньшая контрастность, свойственная практически всем нынешним читалкам с сенсорным экраном, то это самый дешёвый вариант на рынке. Да ещё и с пластиковым (более крепким, чем стекло) экраном.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Айчиталка&#34; — букрикдер imobilco за 6 тысяч рублей</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-08-31-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 20:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-08-31-8/</guid>
      <description>Внимание! За 5999 рублей.
Цитата из релиза:
«О, «Айчиталка» — это чудо, все будут носить ее в этом сезоне. Книга на электронных чернилах, но с чувствительным экраном. Весит всего ничего, но с mp3 проигрывателем. В ней стоит полноценный wifi модуль, который позволяет прямо с «Айчиталки» выходить в интернет и смотреть любые сайты — хотя делать это на черно-белом небольшом экране в наше время странно. Зато там будет стоять специальная программка, черный ход в магазин Аймобилко, через который можно будет будет покупать книжки и тут же читать их.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>99 баксов за букридер. Уже не распродажа</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-08-31-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 14:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-08-31-4/</guid>
      <description>As competition in the e-books device market heats up, Borders is cutting the prices of its leading eReading devices, the Kobo and Aluratek to $129 and $99.99 respectively. The Kobo was previously priced at $149.99 and the Aluratek was priced at $119.99.
 via techcrunch.com
Подтверждения на сайте Borders не нашёл. Но логично.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Читалка Bookeen Cybook Opus за $79</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-08-26-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 07:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-08-26-40/</guid>
      <description>via mediabistro.com
Таааак. Пошло соревнование — кто меньше? Публика интересуется — когда уже начнут доплачивать?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Потолок пробит сверху: Sony Reader Pocket Edition за $99.99</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-08-20-157/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 12:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-08-20-157/</guid>
      <description>And, lo, the era of the sub-$100 e-book reader is finally upon us! Sears (Sears?) has the Sony Reader Pocket Edition PRS-300BC for $99.99 (plus $7 for shipping and sales tax in some states). It&amp;rsquo;s new, not refurbished.
 via news.cnet.com
Похоже, конечно, скорее, на распродажу.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Дожили. LCD-читалка за 99 баксов</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-07-29-56/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 20:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-07-29-56/</guid>
      <description>A small manufacturer already plans to introduce a $99 device this fall. Copia, a subsidiary of DMC Worldwide, is set to offer a $99, 5-inch color e-reader when its line of devices comes to market later this year.
 via blogs.wsj.com
Фигня, видимо, редкостная. Но с цветным экранчиком и за 99 баксов.
Видимо, скоро будут и за 49.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Рязанская область намерена производить электронную бумагу | The-eBook</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-07-18-181/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2010 11:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-07-18-181/</guid>
      <description>Рязанская область борется за размещение предприятия по производству «электронной бумаги». Об этом сообщил губернатор Олег Ковалев во вторник, 13 июля, на встрече с главными редакторами региональных печатных и интернет-СМИ. «Пока у нас есть один очень сильный конкурент – это Питер», – отметил губернатор.
Олег Ковалев рассказал, что Рязанская область совместно с корпорацией «Роснано» планирует создать венчурный фонд, который займется финансированием высокотехнологичных проектов. «Мы хотим двинуть те естественные преимущества, которые есть в Рязанской области», – отметил губернатор, пояснив, что речь идет прежде всего о рязанских ученых, специалистах в области телерадиоэлектроники и предприятиях, работающих в этой отрасли.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ещё дин упавший вниз: Cool-er закрывается</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-07-16-65/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 09:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-07-16-65/</guid>
      <description>via guardian.co.uk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Дисплей iPad против Pixel-Qi на солнце</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-06-30-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 07:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-06-30-53/</guid>
      <description>via e-ink-info.com
У айпад дисплей блекнет на солнце, конечно. Вопрос - как будет с сетчатым дисплеем. А внедрение Пиксель-Чи тормозится. Оно и понятно - надо менять поставщиков, а вдруг что, технология новая. Лучше бы Apple их купил - толку бы больше было.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindle и B&amp;N сбросили цены</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-06-21-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 20:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-06-21-92/</guid>
      <description>Both Amazon and Barnes &amp;amp; Noble dropped the prices of their dedicated e-book readers Monday, no doubt to compete with the likes of the iPad. Amazon now offers its 3G-enabled Kindle 2 for $189, while Barnes &amp;amp; Noble&amp;rsquo;s 3G-enabled nook is now $199—both were previously priced at $259. Additionally, Barnes &amp;amp; Noble has introduced a WiFi-only Nook that will retail for $149.
 via arstechnica.com
Kindle 2: $259 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; $189</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Замени ЖК-дисплей на Pixel Qi сам!</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-03-10-235/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 09:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-03-10-235/</guid>
      <description>Pixel Qi will offer DIY kits towards the end of Q2. Yeah, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to turn your laptop/netbook display into a Pixel Qi display yourself! They say it&amp;rsquo;s rather easy: &amp;ldquo;It’s only slightly more difficult than changing a lightbuld: it’s basically 6 screws, pulling off a bezel, unconnecting the old screen and plugging this one in. That’s it. It’s a 5 minute operation&amp;rdquo;.
 via e-ink-info.com
Забавный способ продвижения.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PocketBook и Освiта уже двигают в школы</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-01-20-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 09:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-01-20-4/</guid>
      <description>via osvitapublish.com.ua
В общем — логично. Чем беднее страна, тем более она готова к восприятию новых технологий. Примерно так же, как с VoIP в &amp;ldquo;третьем мире&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Pocketbook 901 на CES 2010 - 9,7 экран из пластика</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-01-15-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 10:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-01-15-2/</guid>
      <description>via mobileread.com
Примечательно, что демонстрируют — украинский учебник английского языка для 7 класса средней школы.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notecasts.com: книги для iPod Classic и Nano</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-01-05-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 15:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-01-05-1/</guid>
      <description>Macworld UK (@MacworldUK)
1/5/10 17:35
New Application Store for the iPod Classic, iPod Video and iPod launched - www.Notescasts.com
Sent with Tweetie</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Первые картинки Skiff - «херстовского» ридера для СМИ</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-01-04-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 22:25:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-01-04-1/</guid>
      <description>via businessinsider.com
Дисплей 11,5 дюймов. Разрешение 1200 х 1600. Гибкий дисплей производства LG на фольге. Симпатично. Вопрос цены.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PocketBook 301. Типа, щастье</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-31-118/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 01:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-31-118/</guid>
      <description>Только вот то, что USB надо подключать при включённом букридере, в мануале было не написано ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notion Ink Tablet - первая таблетка с диспелеем Pixel Qi Display. Обещают показать на CES&#39;10</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-28-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 01:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-28-100/</guid>
      <description>via epapercentral.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>В продаже появился ONYX BOOX 60</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-27-162/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2009 00:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-27-162/</guid>
      <description>via onyx-boox.ru
теперь в сомнениях: wacom + wifi (webkit) - это недурно за 13 т. сыровато, естественно, судя по форуму на mobileread. ну, может, будет возможность потыкать.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Тайваньские производители объединились в Лигу электронного чтения. Для чего?</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-22-152/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 14:12:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-22-152/</guid>
      <description>After the Executive Yuan included e-book into the cultural and creative department as one of the six emerging industries, Ministry of Economic Affairs stepped up the efforts today. As the Taipei Computer Association took the lead, Acer, Quanta, Acer Communications and Dentsu also joined more than 200 enterprises in the “Electronic Reading Industry League with the fist to establish a common e-book format.
Du Zi-jun, Secretary of Industrial Development Bureau, Ministry of Economic Affairs noted that first we should take the EPUB format into circumspect consideration to follow the international standard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Подписка на Wall Street Journal владельцам нового PRS-900 Sony Daily Edition</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-17-119/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 22:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-17-119/</guid>
      <description>Sony announced Thursday morning that it will sell subscriptions to the digital edition of the Journal as well as a daily summary of news events available only to owners of the Sony device. In addition, users will be able to subscribe to a daily summary of news stories and columns from MarketWatch.com, which like the Journal is owned by Dow Jones &amp;amp; Co.
The Journal summary will cost $5 a month on top of the $14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ролик про eDGe. Симпатично, но дорого</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-16-132/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 12:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-16-132/</guid>
      <description>via news.cnet.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>600 dpi для букридера к 2015 году и закат бумажного книгоиздания?</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-15-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 13:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-15-b/</guid>
      <description>As you may know, the current generation of book readers uses the E-Ink technology, which currently does B&amp;amp;W 800 x 640 on a flexible substrate. They project that color E-Ink devices will become available no earlier than 2011. Hi-res is important: readability studies shows that paper with 600 dpi is the gold standard. a 600 dpi 8 x 10 page is 4800 x 6000 pixels, which is still a pretty big image even for today’s computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Таблетки или букридеры? Решит 2010 год</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-15-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 12:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-15-c/</guid>
      <description>In an ideal world, huge amounts of content in EPUB format would come together with inexpensive, color, touch-enabled e-readers, making them solid textbook replacements and turning giant student backpacks into thin messenger bags.
This is hardly an ideal world, though. Yes, it looks like the inexpensive color e-reader will be a reality, but the same technology will also enable inexpensive color tablets. What is a school going to buy? A one-trick pony e-reader for its students or a really useful convergence device for a slight upcharge?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Мобильники перспективнее букридеров</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-08-97/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2009 21:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-08-97/</guid>
      <description>App Attack: Mobile Reading
 Though we’ve recently noticed a few more Kindles on the subway, mobile phones are infinitely more common. As more consumers choose to read e-books on their smartphones rather than purchase standalone e-reading devices, publishers are working to create apps and other iPhone-ready content.
 Большой обзор растущего рынка.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony Reader окончательно переходит на EPUB 11/12/2009</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-08-145/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2009 15:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-08-145/</guid>
      <description>Sony Reader Store goes 100% EPUB on Friday &amp;ndash; Engadget
 Listen up Sony Reader owners: you&amp;rsquo;ve got three days to change your ways. On December 11th, the eBook Store from Sony will be renamed the Reader Store with a new URL to prove it. In addition to a new store layout, the change also extends the open EPUB format to Sony&amp;rsquo;s entire inventory of eBooks. In fact, any new electronic books will only be available in EPUB which helps explain the motivation for Sony&amp;rsquo;s PRS-500 trade-in program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EPUB победил: Тайвань и Китай договорились о поддержке EPUB</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-02-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 21:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-02-52/</guid>
      <description>China and Taiwan Agree to Promote EPUB E-book Standard - PC World
 China and Taiwan agreed in principal to promote the EPUB e-book format for the Chinese-language market at a technology conference last week, and officials plan to meet again next year to solidify the deal, Taiwan&amp;rsquo;s economics ministry said Wednesday.
 Если учесть величину китайского рынка и то простое обстоятельство, что все букридеры (пока, во всяком случае) делаются именно там, то теперь можно со всей определенностью утверждать, что EPUB и вправду стал индустриальным стандартом.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Тайвань со следующего года внедряет в школы букридеры</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-11-30-150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 09:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-11-30-150/</guid>
      <description>Taiwan Plans to Roll out E-readers in Schools - PC World
 Taiwan&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Education plans to offer e-readers to schoolkids on the island next year as part of efforts to further digitize schools and promote reading. The e-readers are part of a five-year, NT$50 billion (US$1.55 billion) budget earmarked for information technology in classrooms. Currently the ministry is reviewing designs for e-readers and doesn&amp;rsquo;t yet know how many it will purchase for next year, a representative said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Конец 2010 года: цветной букридер с видео от Qualcomm</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-11-18-128/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 22:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-11-18-128/</guid>
      <description>Qualcomm mirasol color video ebook readers to ship in 2010 - SlashGear
 Ebook readers are arguably coming of age, but don’t assume e-ink – and the push to produce color e-ink panels – have won the game quite yet. SlashGear met up with Qualcomm’s mirasol team today to discuss their latest display news, and while you might remember the technology from their early 1.1-inch single-color panels, they’re now showing off a 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iRiver Story</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-11-11-74/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 13:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-11-11-74/</guid>
      <description>iRiver Story. Уже в России Говорят, в розницу будет 12 тысяч. Дорого.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Рынок букридеров стал напоминать метро в час пик</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-11-02-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 23:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-11-02-a/</guid>
      <description>Marvell Syncs With E Ink On New E-Reader Tech Aimed At Mass Market | paidContent
 The e-reader market is beginning to resemble a crowded subway train at rush hour and the latest entry could make it feel even more crowded. Marvell Technology Group and E Ink are partnering on a “turnkey” tech solution based on one integrated chip called the Marvell Armada 166E, with the first devices due in 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Двухэкранный букридер на Android</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-10-19-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2009 20:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-10-19-43/</guid>
      <description>Spring Design
 Spring Design today announced Alex™, the first Google Android-based e-book with full browser capabilities and patented dual screen, the Duet Navigator™. Alex, the first Google Android-based e-book device to provide full Internet browsing over Wi-Fi or mobile networks such as 3G, EVDO/CDMA and GSM. Alex™ features a 6&amp;quot; E-Ink EPD display and 3.5&amp;quot; color LCD display, earphones and speakers. A removable SD card will free up library space on the device while letting users archive content for future reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China Mobile и букридеры</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-10-06-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 16:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-10-06-37/</guid>
      <description>China Mobile Should Have a Head Start in E-Reader Race &amp;ndash; Seeking Alpha
 Meanwhile Jinke is also looking further afield, having already reached a deal with France Telecom to distribute its Hanlin reader in Europe via Orange MNC business units and is looking to target BRIC partner countries, Brazil, Russia and India in the near future.
 Там еще любопытная новость о том, что Китай собирался закупить аж сразу 165 млн букридеров - для учащихся.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUO - новый игрок на рынке букридеров</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-10-05-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2009 10:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-10-05-21/</guid>
      <description>FT.com / Technology - AUO to kindle rivalry with half-price e-readers
 Taiwan’s AU Optronics has thrown down the gauntlet to its rivals, saying it expects to be able to halve the cost of electronic readers, popularised by Amazon’s Kindle devices, within two years.
The world’s third-biggest flat-panel maker has begun shipping six- to nine-inch-sized e-readers to a number of clients, according to CT Liu, a senior vice-president of consumer product displays at AUO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Об iRex в США</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-09-24-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2009 20:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-09-24-72/</guid>
      <description>четверг, 24 сентября 2009 года, 10.38
Владимир Харитонов iRex будет третьим
На массовый рынок электронных книг в США выходит европейский игрок
На рынке электронных книг в США серьёзное оживление. Ещё недавно большую часть рынка контролировали местный Kindle от Amazon и японский Sony Reader со своим магазином электронных книг. Остальных можно было почти не принимать в расчёт. В октябре, однако, в США начнутся массовые продажи букридера iRex производства Philips. Букридер появится не в одиночку — у него за спиной оператор Verizon и главный конкурент Amazon — книготорговая сеть Barnes &amp;amp; Noble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iRex начинает продажи в США</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-09-23-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 09:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-09-23-73/</guid>
      <description>Best Buy and Verizon Jump Into E-Reader Fray, With iRex - NYTimes.comНа американский массовый рынок выходит iRex. Букридер с 8-дюймовым сенсорным экраном, 3G-модемом, международной связью с Verizon и встроенным магазином от Barnes&amp;amp;Noble по цене $399 будет продаваться в более чем 1000 магазинов Best Buy по всем США. Это очевидный конкурент и Kindle DX, и Sony Reader Daily Edition. Кстати, по прогнозам iSuppli в этом году будет продано около 5,2 млн букридеров (из них более половины — в Северной Америке).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ну, вот, это и случилось</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-09-23-56/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 07:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-09-23-56/</guid>
      <description>В Евросети у м. Алексеевская продается букридер. Правда, Orsio за 13400 (онлайн дешевле, а в Ебурге, например, даже дороже), а не PocketBook 360 за 9900. Но всё равно. Скорее всего, продажи будут не ахти, и товар снимут. Но потом букридеры появятся опять - уже дешевле 10 тыс. В общем, &amp;ldquo;февральская&amp;rdquo; революция.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Господдержка производства букридеров. Тайвань</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-09-16-151/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-09-16-151/</guid>
      <description>Taiwan government aims at 80% global market share for Taiwan-made e-book readers in 2013
 Taiwan&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Economic Affairs (MOEA) will be implementing a 5-year project with a total budget of NT$2.134 billion (US$65 million) to boost development of digital publication industries in Taiwan, with the goal being to make Taiwan-produced e-book readers reach a global market share of 80% with sales of NT$50 billion in 2013, according to the agency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Times о букридерах</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-09-08-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2009 22:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-09-08-50/</guid>
      <description>FT.com | Tech Blog | How electronic paper displays are stacking up
 there are now more than 45 e-reader models available worldwide, according to E Ink, the dominant technology provider for their displays.
  “This year, we’ve already seen a $199 product, I wouldn’t be surprised if next year someone launched a product at around $159 and, three or four years from now, a $99 product.” (Sriram Peruvemba, marketing vice president at E Ink) Colour is coming next year, with E Ink laying a colour filter over its monochrome display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asus готовит букридер с двумя экранами за 100 фунтов</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-09-07-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 10:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-09-07-19/</guid>
      <description>Tech news: For the smarter kind of bookworm - Times Online
 Unlike current ebook readers, which take the form of a single flat screen, the Asus device has a hinged spine, like a printed book. This, in theory, enables its owner to read an ebook much like a normal book, using the touchscreen to “turn” the pages from one screen to the next. It also gives the user the option of seeing the text on one screen while browsing a web page on the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>В Россию придёт &#34;корейский Kindle&#34;?</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-09-01-75/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 09:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-09-01-75/</guid>
      <description>iRiver&amp;rsquo;s new e-book reader &amp;lsquo;Story&amp;rsquo; - MobileRead Forums
   С 16 сентября в Южной Корее можно будет заказать букридер Story от старого доброго производителя mp3-плейеров iRiver: 6-дюймовый экран, QWERTY-клавиатура (!), поддержка pdf, epub, txt, ppt, doc, xls без конвертации (!), просмотр комиксов, память, расширяемая до 32 Гб, батарея на 9 тыс &amp;ldquo;перелистываний&amp;rdquo;. Цена около $300. О беспроводных интерфейсах информации пока нет, но клавиатура ведь для чего-то нужна? Интересно, однако, даже не это, а то, что производитель «also talking with retailers in Russia».</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Новый 7&#34; и беспроводной Sony Reader - в декабре</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-08-25-147/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 15:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-08-25-147/</guid>
      <description>Sony Unveils Three Would-Be Kindle Killers—Pocket, Touch and Now, 3G Wireless With AT&amp;amp;T | paidContent
 Sony’s Daily Edition, a 3G powered wireless device meant to go head to head with Kindle. Will ship this December for $399.
 В Рождество начнутся продажи нового Sony Reader - Daily Edition: 7-дюймовый экран (кажется, все же маловат для газет) и беспроводная 3G-связь (в США - через AT&amp;amp;T). $399</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Новости от Sony: снижение цен на букридеры и электронные книги</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-08-04-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 22:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-08-04-101/</guid>
      <description>Sony Cuts Prices on E-Books and Unveils Readers - NYTimes.com
 Sony Electronics plans to announce on Tuesday that it is lowering prices for new and bestselling books in its e-book store, to $9.99 from $11.99. Sony is also introducing two new electronic reading devices: the Reader Pocket Edition and Reader Touch Edition. They will sell for $199 and $299 respectively and will go on sale at the end of August.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AT&amp;T обеспечит связь для букридера Plastic Logic</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-07-22-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 20:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-07-22-20/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T to Power Plastic Logic E-Reader - Digits - WSJ
 AT&amp;amp;T said Wednesday that it will provide the 3G data connectivity for Plastic Logic’s e-reader when the device becomes available next year.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Полномасштабный запуск цветной электронной бумаги намечен на 2010 год</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-05-12-121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 10:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-05-12-121/</guid>
      <description>Epaper Central Talks with E Ink’s VP Sriram K. Peruvemba - Epaper Central
 E Ink is targeting the end of 2010 for commercial launch of our color displays. We will demonstrate color displays in the meanwhile at the SID (Society for Information Display) show in San Antonio, Texas from June 2-5.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Скоро появится Amazon Kindle для газет</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-05-04-143/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 10:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-05-04-143/</guid>
      <description>Big-Screen e-Readers May Help Save Newspapers - NYTimes.com
 But it is Amazon, maker of the Kindle, that appears to be first in line to try throwing an electronic life preserver to old-media companies. As early as this week, according to people briefed on the online retailer’s plans, Amazon will introduce a larger version of its Kindle wireless device tailored for displaying newspapers, magazines and perhaps textbooks. An Amazon spokesman would not comment, but some news organizations, including The New York Times, are expected to be involved in the introduction of the device, according to people briefed on the plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Вот вам и цветной букридер</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-03-18-165/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 20:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-03-18-165/</guid>
      <description>Fujitsu FLEPia released! - MobileRead Forums
 Featuring an 8-inch XGA screen capable of displaying 260,000 colors, along with Bluetooth, WiFi and up to 4GB of storage via SD card, and measuring less than half an inch thick, FLEPia&amp;rsquo;s not just getting by on color alone. Fujitsu promises 40 hours of continuos use, and the unit can be operated by its touchscreen or the assortment of function buttons. &amp;hellip; FLEPia ships on April 20th in Japan for 99,750 Yen (about $1,010 US).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Букридеры ORSiO будут понимать epub</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-02-16-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 22:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-02-16-34/</guid>
      <description>В электронной переписке представитель компании ORSiO сообщил, что программисты компании планирует расширить ряд форматов, которые понимает производимый компанией букридер, за счет epub. Начинание можно только приветствовать — формат быстро наьирает популярность. Последняя версия ORSiO исполльзует тот же экран, что и Sony Reader, так что у ORSiO есть все шансы стать его достойным конкурентом — тем более, что все форматы этот букридер понимает без дополнительной конвертации.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>И сколько же эта радость будет стоить со всеми ее фичами?</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-01-24-65/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2009 16:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-01-24-65/</guid>
      <description>Announcing the txtr reader : blog.txtr.com
 * The latest 6-inch eInk display for maximum readability
* Advanced power management guaranteeing weeks of reading time
* Full connectivity including USB, Bluetooth, and true mobility with SIM-enabled UMTS/GPRS
* An user interface that will blow away everything you’ve seen on eInk so far
* Of course, tight integration with txtr.com
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>800 газет на букридере iRex</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-12-06-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 23:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-12-06-a/</guid>
      <description>E-Reads: Digi-Newspaper Scoreboard: Kindle 28, Kindle Killer 800
 It&amp;rsquo;s a good time to be alive if you&amp;rsquo;re a tree. Digitally delivered news is gaining momentum and as we turn the corner to 2009 it&amp;rsquo;s gotten a rocket boost from the Dutch firm iRex Technologies, which announced it has made a deal with NewspaperDirect to deliver 800 newspapers on iRex&amp;rsquo;s Digital Reader 1000.
 iRex договорился с NewspaperDirect о том, что с 11 декабря 2008 года пользователям букридера iRex 1000 будет доступна подписка на 800 газет со всего мира в электронном формате для чтения на этом устройстве.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>За два года продано 300 тыс Sony Reader</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-12-04-57/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 20:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-12-04-57/</guid>
      <description>Business Technology : Turns Out Sony E-Book Readers Sell After All
 Sony for the first time disclosed that it sold 300,000 units of its Reader Digital Book globally since the device launched in October 2006.
 Via MobileRead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony представила букридер с сенсорным управлением</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-10-03-47/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 07:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-10-03-47/</guid>
      <description>Компьюлента. Новости науки и техники.
 Sony представила электронную книгу нового поколения с поддержкой сенсорного управления
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Анонс EZ Reader от Astak и Jinke</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-09-27-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 10:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-09-27-5/</guid>
      <description>Astak&amp;rsquo;s press release for the EZ Reader - MobileRead Forums Компания Astak объявила о начале продаж в ноябре первого устройства из серии букридеров EZ Reader. Первый EZ Reader будет иметь 6-дюймовый экран. Производитель — Jinke, то есть это lBook для американцев.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Будущий ридер для бизнес-пользователей</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-09-15-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 14:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-09-15-8/</guid>
      <description>На конференции DEMOFall&#39;09 английская компания Plastic Logic презентовала большой экран на электронных чернилах. Нетрудно заметить, что устройство ориентировано по преимуществу на бизнес-пользователей и их потребности в чтении большого числа деловых бумаг. Не удивлюсь, если такое устройство когда-нибудь окрестят «бизнес-ридером»: И еще обзорная статья об устройстве в Technology Review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Букридер Sony Reader: новая прошивка, новые форматы, новые рынки</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-07-24-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2008 14:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-07-24-10/</guid>
      <description>За последние несколько дней в новостных лентах, на тематических блогах и форумах появилось сразу несколько новостей о Sony Reader: PRS505 Firmware update: epub, DE, and reflow &amp;ndash; oh my! - MobileRead Forums: После сегодняшнего пакета обновления прошивки букридер сможет понимать формат EPUB . Кроме того, для закачки в него электронных книг (в формате EPUB и PDF) можно будет использовать Adobe Digital Edition. Sony Reader UK preorder opens tomorrow - MobileRead Forums: Букридер вскоре начнет продаваться в Англиии и, возможно, в России.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone как конкурент букридеру: экономический аспект</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-07-10-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2008 15:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-07-10-17/</guid>
      <description>Publishing Frontier » Blog Archive » ebooks and the iPhone
 Одна из проблем устройств, подобных Sony Reader и Kindle состоит в том, что они вступают в конкуренцию с другими «платформами» для чтения, например, книгой в обложке или книгой из библиотеки. Стоит ли тратить $300 на заменитель книги, который хрупок, в котором может кончиться батарейка и который жалко калечить неблагоприятным окружением (к примеру, на пляже)? Ведь можно купить книжику в мягкой обложке на распродаже за $5 или просто взять в библиотеке бесплатно.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>На российском рынке появился новый букридер — ORSiO</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-07-07-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-07-07-33/</guid>
      <description>На сайте The-eBook Russia опубликован подробный, содержательный и, в целом, весьма позитивный отчет о тестировании букридера с экраном из электронной бумаги ORSiO b721, продажи которого начинаются в России. Судя по отзывам экспертов, с точки зрения аппаратной начинки устройство — родной брат французского CyBook и Explay TXT.Book: вес 176 г, экран 6&amp;quot; (800 х 600 пикселей), интерфейс USB 2.0. Однако с точки зрения программной начинки может дать им фору, понимая файлы в форматах HTML, TXT, FB2, RTF, DjVu и PDF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lBook в розничной продаже</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-07-04-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 19:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-07-04-23/</guid>
      <description>The-eBook Russia » Blog Archive » В “Союзе” есть еще пока, устройства лучше чем всегда!
 LBook&amp;hellip; ждет своего покупателя в сети магазинов СОЮЗ.
 9990 р. Еще дорого, но все равно — отличная новость. Еще немного — и в «Евросети».</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Букридер для домохозяек</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-07-27-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 10:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-07-27-9/</guid>
      <description>Букридеры на электронной бумаге — вовсе не единственные устройства, которые можно использовать для чтения электронных книг. Критичен только удобный интерфейс (в том числе подходящие размеры, разрешение и качество экрана) и программное обеспечение, позволяющее читать книги. В этом смысле недорогой ($130) гаджет MiBook который в скором времени выпускает на рынок компания Photoco, с 7-дюймовым экраном может еще одним конкурентом для Amazon Kindle и Sony Reader. The miBook from Photoco - NYTimes.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Эксперименты с двухэкранными электронными книгами</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-01-26-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2008 15:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-01-26-2/</guid>
      <description>Соответствующему исследованию ученых из Университета Мэриленда и Беркли посвящена статья в New Scientist Technology Blog: Dual-display e-book reader lets you flip pages naturally.
Доклад «Способы обращения с двухдисплейными букридерами» см.: http://www.cs.umd.edu/%7Efrancois/Papers/EBookReaderCHI08.pdf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Прекрасное далёко: ePaper и One Laptop Per Child-2</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-05-24-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 07:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-05-24-12/</guid>
      <description>За последнюю неделю появилось еще две примечательные новости, касающиеся будущего технологий электронного книгоиздания.
Компания Epson на выставке SID 2008 в Лос-Анджелесе представила образец электронной бумаги формата A4 (3104 × 4128 пикселей, разрешение 385ppi). Образец был разработан в сотрудничестве с E Ink Corp. Электронная бумага таких размеров может претендовать на то, чтобы быть заменой бумажным черно-белым газетам. Однако говорить об этом пока рановато применительно к этому образцу: он сделан на стеклянной основе.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Статья про букридеры в «Ведомостях»</title>
      <link>/posts/2008-05-20-55/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 19:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2008-05-20-55/</guid>
      <description>Наконец долгожданный отпуск! Вы пакуете чемодан и составляете список того, что хотелось бы прочитать, валяясь на пляже. Эту книгу рекомендовали друзья, а вот интересная новинка, и эту книгу давно надо дочитать, а еще… Стоп! Книги уже не помещаются в сумку. Что же делать? Взять с собой электронную книгу
Зачем нужны электронные книги, если имеются почти универсальные КПК? Тут тебе и органайзер, и электронная почта, и записная книжка, и плейер, туда же можно закачать и текст книги.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
