<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft on Новости электронного книгоиздания</title>
    <link>/tags/microsoft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft on Новости электронного книгоиздания</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 13:31:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft разрабатывает новую обложку для Lumia —  с eInk-экраном</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-02-08-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 13:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2016-02-08-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Research is currently in deep talks with the Lumia team in Finland to develop a secondary e ink screen inside of the Flip Covers. Microsoft said they&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://goodereader.com/blog/e-paper/microsoft-is-developing-a-secondary-e-ink-screen-for-lumia-smartphones&#34;&gt;Microsoft is developing a secondary e-Ink screen for Lumia smartphones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Этак Lumia станет совсем симпатичным телефоном. Ещё бы Android-приложения туда можно было ставить — и совсем must have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Режим чтения в виде книги??? Microsoft представила новый браузер Edge</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-04-29-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 20:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2015-04-29-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Представитель компании рассказал о нововведениях браузера. Среди них - возможность создавать заметки на веб-странице и делиться ими с комментариями, &lt;strong&gt;новый режим чтения, который форматирует страницы в книгу или журнал&lt;/strong&gt;, а также чтение страниц в режиме офлайн и интеграция с голосовым помощником Cortana.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slon.ru/posts/51072&#34;&gt;Microsoft представила новый браузер Edge / Slon.ru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft вкладывает в Nook $300 млн</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-04-30-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 11:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2012-04-30-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has invested $300m (£184.5m) in Barnes and Noble, forming “a new subsidiary” of the bookselling chain to include the store’s Nook, digital and college business.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thebookseller.com/news/microsoft-invests-bn-capitalise-nook.html&#34;&gt;thebookseller.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft немного даже жалко — догоняет на рынок. Но эти деньги B&amp;amp;N явно будут не лишние в конкуренции c Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R. I. P. lit</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-08-15-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 21:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2011-08-15-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is discontinuing Microsoft Reader effective August 30, 2012, which includes download access of the Microsoft Reader application from the Microsoft Reader website. However, customers may continue to use and access the Microsoft Reader application and any .lit materials on their PCs or devices after the discontinuation on August 30, 2012. New content for purchase from retailers in the .lit format will be discontinued on November 8, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/reader/default.aspx&#34;&gt;microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Кто-нибудь ещё помнит, что это формат электронных книжек для программы Microsoft Reader? Теперь можно спокойно, вспомнив, забыть навсегда. Хобби Microsoft так и не стало бизнесом. Может быть, потому что появилось слишком рано. Может быть, потому что Microsoft. Don&amp;rsquo;t be evil, и люди к тебе потянутся.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O&#39;Reilly берет на себя Microsoft Press</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-09-24-110/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2009 20:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2009-09-24-110/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://press.oreilly.com/pub/pr/2413&#34;&gt;O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media and Microsoft Announce Plans to Expand Microsoft Press: O&amp;rsquo;Reilly to Distribute Microsoft Press Titles and Launch New Ebook Initiatives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media, Inc. and Microsoft Corp. today announced a joint arrangement to support and expand Microsoft Press from production through distribution, co-publishing and content development, marketing and management. Through this strategic relationship, on November 30, O&amp;rsquo;Reilly will become the distributor of Microsoft Press titles in North America with a global roll out in a phased approach. Both O&amp;rsquo;Reilly and Microsoft will develop Microsoft Press titles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
