<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>history on Новости электронного книгоиздания</title>
    <link>/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in history on Новости электронного книгоиздания</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 09:02:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Проект Gutenberg. 50 тысяч книг</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-10-06-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 09:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-10-06-a/</guid>
      <description>Project Gutenberg is thrilled to achieve the milestone of eBook #50,000. In honor of Project Gutenberg&amp;rsquo;s founder, Michael S. Hart, a special title was selected. &amp;ldquo;John Gutenberg, First Master Printer, His Acts, and most remarkable Discourses, and his Death&amp;rdquo; is now available at www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/50000. Johannes (or John) Gutenberg is best known for introducing mechanical movable type printing to Europe. This brought about a revolution in printing, which was a key event in shaping today&amp;rsquo;s information and knowlege-based society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Механическая читалка, XVI век</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-08-31-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 13:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-08-31-a/</guid>
      <description> As early as 1588, the Italian military engineer Agostino Ramelli invented a device that allowed people to read multiple books at the same time, without having
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Так вот откуда появились ISBN…</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-07-20-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 11:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-07-20-a/</guid>
      <description>In the second of our series of articles about the International Standard Book Number system, Richard Charkin talks to David Whitaker, who chaired the panel which planned the Standard Book Number system, which was introduced in the UK in 1967 and which subsequently evolved into the ISBN system […]
 Source: International Publishers Association - &amp;ldquo;It was an idea whose time had come.&amp;rdquo; David Whitaker on the birth of ISBN</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ничего святого: проанализировали «запах старых книг»</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-01-18-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 16:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-01-18-a/</guid>
      <description>That “Old Book Smell” is a Mix of Grass and Vanilla | Smart News.
Главная составляющая запаха старых бумажных книг — результат разложения лигнина, близкого по своему химическому составу ванилину. Старые книги пахнут ванилью. Так они борются за своё сохранение.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Не могу не запостить</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-04-10-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 22:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-04-10-b/</guid>
      <description>В книге всякие ништяки. Автор рулит. Недаром один из создателей Kindle.
P. S. Автограф, хоть и цифровой, но настоящий. Ништяк )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ролик старый. Но такой красивый</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-11-28-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 23:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-11-28-a/</guid>
      <description>A short vignette of a book being created using traditional printing methods.
For the Daily Telegraph. Shot at Smith-Settle Printers, Leeds, England. The book being printed is Suzanne St Albans’ &amp;lsquo;Mango and Mimosa&amp;rsquo; published as part of the Slightly Foxed series.
Shot, Directed &amp;amp; Edited by Glen Milner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>К вопросу об истоках мобильных компьютеров: дизайн-проект 1982 года</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-04-16-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 11:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-04-16-a/</guid>
      <description>via futureofthebook.org
Intelligent Encyclopedia, которую Боб Штайн с Аланом Кеем из Atari и Гленом Кином из Disney придумали в в 1982 году.
По виду больше похоже на нетбук ;-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodak подаёт на банкротство</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-01-04-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 21:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-01-04-a/</guid>
      <description>digital happened.
 via thenextweb.com
У Брюса Стерлинга есть очень правильная тема — «мертвые технологии». И в блоге, и в одном из романов, в «Священном огне», кажется.
Кинокамеры перестали производить ещё в прошлом году. Теперь вот Kodak. Цифра вторгается в жизнь и всё переделывает под себя. Кто не смог присвоить это вторжение — обречён. Или будет процветать как реинкарнация винила и поляроида.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We might as well call it: Cinema as we knew it is dead</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-10-15-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 19:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-10-15-2/</guid>
      <description>An article at the moviemaking technology website Creative Cow reports that the three major manufacturers of motion picture film cameras — Aaton, ARRI and Panavision — have all ceased production of new cameras within the last year, and will only make digital movie cameras from now on. As the article’s author, Debra Kaufman, poignantly puts it, “Someone, somewhere in the world is now holding the last film camera ever to roll off the line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>В отличие от Столмена, Парфри объективен</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-10-07-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 19:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-10-07-2/</guid>
      <description>Steve Jobs and his Apple Empire was a great thing for Feral House …. for a while. His 512 K “Fat Mac” enabled us to to typeset and design books without going through the too-costly route of paying for text created on a Compugraphic typesetting device. (We must also thank a Mr. Stephen Bates who created the beta software “Just Text” which was the first program to allow its users to create elegant Postscript type, about a million times better than the usual crappy dot-matrix computer fonts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Скончался Майкл Харт, отец электронных книг и основатель Project Gutenberg</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-09-08-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 04:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-09-08-2/</guid>
      <description>6 сентября умер Майкл Харт, основатель проекта Гутенберг. Ему было 64 года.
Первую электронную книгу, «Декларацию независимости США», он набил сам на телетайпе.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Кодекс как опыт нелинейного чтения</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-09-04-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2011 19:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-09-04-1/</guid>
      <description>God knows, there was great literature before there was the codex, and should it pass away, there will be great literature after it. But if we stop reading on paper, we should keep in mind what we’re sacrificing: that nonlinear experience, which is unique to the codex. You don’t get it from any other medium — not movies, or TV, or music or video games. The codex won out over the scroll because it did what good technologies are supposed to do: It gave readers a power they never had before, power over the flow of their own reading experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1DollarScan сканирует книжки на заказ</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-08-15-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 15:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-08-15-b/</guid>
      <description>А потом в макулатуру. И еще срезают корешок перед сканированием. Теперь, после Японии, и в США. Бакс за сто страниц. Ужас. В России такой бизнес запрещён.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>И ещё к 100-летию Маклюэна: медаиархив</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-07-22-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 09:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-07-22-1/</guid>
      <description>via marshallmcluhanspeaks.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 лет Маршаллу Маклюэну</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-07-21-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 21:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-07-21-a/</guid>
      <description>The extensions of man’s consciousness induced by the electric media could conceivably usher in the millennium, but it also holds the potential for realizing the Anti-Christ.
 via kk.org</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Хочу на экскурсию в Блечли-Парк</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-05-27-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 13:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-05-27-b/</guid>
      <description>via wired.co.uk
Там восстановили Tunny, комп 1942-го, сделанный путём обратного разработки немецкой машины S42. Это был последний шаг в расшифровке немецких военных шифров.
А благодаря «The Geek Atlas» понятно, как туда добраться.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshall McLuhan Speaks - Centennial 2011</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-01-27-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 10:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-01-27-b/</guid>
      <description>via www2.marshallmcluhanspeaks.com
Хорошая подборка.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Дуглас Коупленд написал биографию Маклюена</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-01-13-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 14:41:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-01-13-b/</guid>
      <description>Marshall McLuhan
Marshall McLuhan: You Know Nothing of My Work! by Douglas Coupland Atlas, 216 pp., $24
 via tnr.com
Must translate, блин.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>За Volkischer Beobachter теперь Hitlerjugend</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-08-20-234/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 13:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-08-20-234/</guid>
      <description>Шевчука ждет облом.
Потому что Макаревич музыкант и предприниматель, потому что Белых политик и оппозиционер.
А Шевчук – ни политик, ни музыкант.
Он – кусок говна!
 via krispotupchik.livejournal.com
В инфо у этого юзера написано &amp;ldquo;пресс-секретарь движения Наши&amp;rdquo;.
Удивительно адекватный юзерпик.
P. S. Непонятно, как эта запись здесь оказалась. Но пусть останется — для истории. Тем более, что Архив интернета не успел закэшировать.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Скандал с Павловской станцией дошёл до NAture</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-08-11-192/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 18:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-08-11-192/</guid>
      <description>One of the 893 blackcurrant varieties in the threatened collection.RIV, Russia
The future of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest repository of rare berries and fruit has been thrown into doubt by a court decision today. Russia&amp;rsquo;s Supreme Arbitration Court in Moscow has ruled against an appeal to preserve Pavlovsk Experimental Station, a federally run gene bank housing more than 5,000 varieties of crop that are hard to breed from seeds and so cannot be stored frozen as in typical seed banks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ъ-Новости - СКП предлагает химическую кастрацию педофилов</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-07-22-126/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 20:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-07-22-126/</guid>
      <description>Глава СКП привел в пример Польшу, где недавно вступил в силу закон, по которому насильников и педофилов могут подвергать химической кастрации
 via kommersant.ru
Почему чиновники в России учатся у Запада только дурному?
P. S. Почему эта запись здесь? Уже не помню. Ну, пусть будет.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad был предсказан 11 лет назад</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-07-16-79/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 06:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-07-16-79/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to strong iMac sales, Steve Jobs is insanely great again, and accolades in the trades have called Apple&amp;rsquo;s reversal of fortune everything from a &amp;ldquo;rebound&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;the Second Coming.&amp;rdquo; The next iMac attack promises new lollipop laptops, a more serious series of professional machines, and a wireless handheld dubbed the iPad. Though it&amp;rsquo;s hard to argue with five straight profitable quarters, Apple&amp;rsquo;s teal-colored turnaround is saddled to a single product line - built on an aging operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Полезная статья о фальстарте электронных книг в начале века</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-02-25-155/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 22:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2010-02-25-155/</guid>
      <description>via publishingtrends.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Кажется, первая книга по истории электронных книг</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-05-140/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 22:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-05-140/</guid>
      <description>Dossiers du NEF - Une courte histoire de l&amp;rsquo;ebook
 A short history of ebooks (pdf, 2009)
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
