<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Public Domain on Новости электронного книгоиздания</title>
    <link>/tags/public-domain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Public Domain on Новости электронного книгоиздания</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 09:46:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/public-domain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Первое января — праздник public domain в США</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-12-24-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 09:46:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2018-12-24-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Первого января 2019 года — большой праздник в США. Из-за запутанной системы авторского права в этот день, впервые за 20 лет в общественное достояние пополнится: в public domain переходят произведения, опубликованные в Штатах в 1923 году:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Edgar Rice Burroughs, &lt;em&gt;Tarzan and the Golden Lion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Agatha Christie, &lt;em&gt;The Murder on the Links&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Winston S. Churchill, &lt;em&gt;The World Crisis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;e.e. cummings, &lt;em&gt;Tulips and Chimneys&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Robert Frost, &lt;em&gt;New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kahlil Gibran, &lt;em&gt;The Prophet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Aldous Huxley, &lt;em&gt;Antic Hay&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;D.H. Lawrence, &lt;em&gt;Kangaroo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bertrand and Dora Russell, &lt;em&gt;The Prospects of Industrial Civilization&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;P.G. Wodehouse, works including &lt;em&gt;The Inimitable Jeeves&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Leave it to Psmith&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;etc. Подробнее см.: &lt;a href=&#34;https://law.duke.edu/cspd/publicdomainday/2019/&#34;&gt;https://law.duke.edu/cspd/publicdomainday/2019/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Проект Gutenberg. 50 тысяч книг</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-10-06-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 09:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2015-10-06-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Project Gutenberg is thrilled to achieve the milestone of eBook #50,000. In honor of Project Gutenberg&amp;rsquo;s founder, Michael S. Hart, a special title was selected. &amp;ldquo;John Gutenberg, First Master Printer, His Acts, and most remarkable Discourses, and his Death&amp;rdquo; is now available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/50000&#34;&gt;www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/50000&lt;/a&gt;. Johannes (or John) Gutenberg is best known for introducing mechanical movable type printing to Europe. This brought about a revolution in printing, which was a key event in shaping today&amp;rsquo;s information and knowlege-based society. Michael Hart invented the electronic book in 1971, launching what would become his life&amp;rsquo;s major calling. He named his effort &amp;ldquo;Project Gutenberg,&amp;rdquo; to recognize the impact of Johannes Gutenberg and in anticipation of electronic books helping to transform society by bringing cost-free literature to all people. Free literature, and the freedom of thought and freedom of expression it fosters, is key to growth of literacy, opportunity and enlightenment. You can&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Отличная картинка для календаря public domain</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-01-29-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 19:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2012-01-29-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sarolta.wordpress.com/2012/01/02/a-happy-public-domain-day/&#34;&gt;sarolta.wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public domain 2012</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-01-01-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 11:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2012-01-01-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Сегодня перешли в общественное достояние опубликованные при жизни сочинения Анри Бергсона, Вирджинии Вулф, Джеймса Фрэзера, Вернера Зомбарта, Бенджамина Уорфа, Рабиндраната Тагора, Марины Цветаевой, Дмитрия Мережковского. Должны были стать общественным достоянием еще и сочинения Аркадия Гайдара, но он воевал во время Великой Отечественной, а значит их &amp;ldquo;освобождение&amp;rdquo; откладывается.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Калькулятор общественного достояния от Европеаны</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-08-17-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 10:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2011-08-17-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.outofcopyright.eu/index.html&#34;&gt;outofcopyright.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Считает по ЕЭС + Норвегия, Швеция и Исландия.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Не слишком удобный пошаговый интерфейс. Но обещали сделать и более удобный.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Исключительно актуальная штука, поскольку - спасибо институту авторского права - определить, находится ли книга в общественном достоянии, нельзя.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;А еще ведь есть и всякие исключения. Например, как с &amp;ldquo;Питером Пэном&amp;rdquo;, роялти за него до сих пор платятся одной английской детской больнице.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Книги Александра Беляева так-таки в общественном достоянии</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-04-15-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 09:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2011-04-15-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;В материалах ФАСМО указано, что срок охраны наследия писателя-фантаста вступил в силу 1 января 1943 года и истек 31 декабря 1992 года, а не после 1993 года, как постановил апелляционный суд, приплюсовав к имеющимся пятидесяти годам еще четыре. Таким образом, «произведения перешли в общественное достояние и в настоящее время охране не подлежат, в связи с чем, нарушение ответчиком прав истца отсутствует. Учитывая, что произведения А. Беляева перешли в разряд произведений общественного достояния, размер компенсации, который оспаривается сторонами, значения не имеет».&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>В общественное достояние с чистой совестью</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-02-06-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 18:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2011-02-06-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Прошерстив «Википедию», обнаружил, что 2011 году в общественное достояние, наконец-то, попали опубликованные при жизни труды Николая Альбертовича Куна, который написал «Легенды и мифы Древней Греции», стихи и переводы Владимира Пяста, а также труды Льва Давидовича Троцкого и Михаила Афанасьевича Булгакова («Мастер и Маргарита» — нет, поскольку была опубликована только после смерти).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Domain Mark - Creative Commons</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-10-13-173/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 21:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2010-10-13-173/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, Creative Commons &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/press-releases/entry/23755&#34;&gt;announces&lt;/a&gt; the release of its &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/mark/1.0/&#34;&gt;Public Domain Mark&lt;/a&gt;, a tool that enables works free of known copyright restrictions to be labeled in a way that allows them to be easily discovered over the Internet. The Public Domain Mark, to be used for marking works already free of copyright, complements Creative Commons’ &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/about/cc0&#34;&gt;CC0 public domain dedication&lt;/a&gt;, which enables authors to relinquish their rights prior to the expiration of copyright.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/23830&#34;&gt;creativecommons.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Не &amp;ldquo;антикопирайт&amp;rdquo;, а &amp;ldquo;общественное достояние&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Открытый регистр книг в public domain. Есть и русские авторы</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-01-14-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 21:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2010-01-14-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.publicdomainworks.net/&#34;&gt;Public Domain Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Public Domain: Enclosing the Commons of the Mind - стоило бы перевести</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-01-14-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 21:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2010-01-14-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0300137400?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=httpthepublio-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0300137400&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.thepublicdomain.org/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/smallcover2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;smallcover2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/88x31.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Public Domain: Enclosing the Commons of the Mind&lt;/em&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you like it, please consider &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0300137400?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=httpthepublio-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0300137400&#34;&gt;buying&lt;/a&gt; a copy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why am I allowing you to copy the book for free?  And why is Yale University Press letting me?   To understand why I am doing it, watch this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1DKm96Ftfko&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; by Jesse Dylan.  And if you want to  understand why it  makes economic sense to my publisher, read this short &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ft.com/cms/s/b46f5a58-aa2e-11db-83b0-0000779e2340.html&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 января - день Public Domain. С прошедшим праздником!</title>
      <link>/posts/2010-01-14-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 21:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2010-01-14-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 1st 2010 — and every January 1st –  is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.law.duke.edu/cspd/publicdomainday&#34;&gt;public domain day&lt;/a&gt;, the day we celebrate the entry of copyrighted works into the public domain.  In the United States &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.law.duke.edu/cspd/publicdomainday&#34;&gt;no published work will pass into the public domain tomorrow&lt;/a&gt; — nor the next year, nor any year until 2019.  (If you lived in Europe you might now be celebrating the release of the works of &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.okfn.org/2009/11/25/which-works-fall-into-the-public-domain-in-2010/&#34;&gt;Freud or Yeats&lt;/a&gt;.)  Thus, we have little to celebrate, and many &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.law.duke.edu/cspd/publicdomainday/whyitmatters&#34;&gt;costs to mourn&lt;/a&gt;.  Its sad to look at the works that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.law.duke.edu/cspd/publicdomainday/pre1976&#34;&gt;could be entering the public domain today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Европейский библиотека растёт</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-17-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 22:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-17-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Europeana’s collection of online European heritage passed the 5 million mark in early December, taking the multilingual digital library, museum and archive over halfway to its target of 10 million searchable items in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Portraits of notable Polish figures, including astronomer Copernicus and composer Frederic Chopin are among the newest additions to Europeana – part of some 257,000 images, texts, videos and sounds that were submitted by regional groups across Poland. The influx takes the proportion of Polish items on Europeana from 0.4 percent of the total to 5.5 percent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
