<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crowdsourcing on Новости электронного книгоиздания</title>
    <link>/tags/crowdsourcing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crowdsourcing on Новости электронного книгоиздания</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 12:19:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/crowdsourcing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amazon запускает краудсорсинг для своей издательской программы</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-09-23-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 12:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2014-09-23-b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Authors will be asked to submit their complete, never-before-published book and cover. After a few days, we will post the first pages of each book on a new website for readers to preview and nominate their favorites. Books with the most nominations will be reviewed by our team for potential publication.Should you be selected for publication you will receive benefits that include:Guaranteed advance &amp;amp; competitive royalties: You will receive a guaranteed $1,500 advance and 50% royalties on net eBook revenue.Focused formats: We acquire worldwide publication rights for eBook and audio formats in all languages. You retain all other rights, including print.5-year renewable terms, $5,000 in royalties: If your book doesn&amp;rsquo;t earn $5,000 in royalties during your initial 5-year contract term, and any 5-year renewal term after that, you can choose to stop publishing with us.Easy reversions: After two years, your rights in any format or language that remains unpublished, or all rights for any book that earns less than $500 in total royalties in the preceding 12-month period, can be reverted upon request - no questions asked.Early downloads &amp;amp; reviews: One week prior to release date, everyone who nominated your book will receive a free, early copy to help build momentum and customer reviews.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
