<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EU on Новости электронного книгоиздания</title>
    <link>/tags/eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EU on Новости электронного книгоиздания</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 19:56:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ну, наконец-то: электронные книги — это книги. С точки зрения налогов в ЕС</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-09-14-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 19:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-09-14-b/</guid>
      <description>Pierre Moscovici, the EU tax commissioner, confirmed on Saturday that the commission would propose legislation to address the matter, saying there was a need to recognise that ebooks “are books”.
 Еврокомиссар по налогам заявил, что в ближайшее время внесёт предложение по изменению налогообложения продаж электронных книг, потому что надо признать, что электронные книги — «это книги». Ну, наконец-то. И это будет означать резкое снижение НДС.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Книжный рынок Европы сократился. Продажи эл.книг выросли</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-12-20-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 12:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-12-20-a/</guid>
      <description>Федерация европейских издателей ФЕИ, FEP, представляющая 28 национальных издательских групп, опубликовала данные по доходам издателей Европы за 2012 год. Общая выручка издательских домов Европе составила €22.5 миллиарда около $30.5 миллиарда, что на 1,3% меньше чем в 2011 году. Этот показатель отображает исключительно продажи книг, не включая в себя продажу международных прав. «Наиболее заметными тенденциями 2012 года стал продолжающийся рост рынка электронных книг отвечающих за 3% от продаж, а также хорошие показатели по экспорту», — утверждается в документе ФЕИ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iBookstore, видимо, нацелился на Европу</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-02-27-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 21:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-02-27-a/</guid>
      <description>Patricia Arancibia has joined Apple as head of the iBookstore&amp;rsquo;s European operations. Previously she was editorial director, International Acquisition &amp;amp; Relations - International Digital Content at Barnes &amp;amp; Noble.
 via People, Etc. | Publishers Lunch.
Во многом благодаря усилиям Патрисии Barnes &amp;amp; Noble сумел сформировать неплохой пакет иностранных книг. Уход оттуда сейчас вполне логичен — непонятно, что будет с Nook Media, — впрочем, это может означать более активные, учитывая энергию Патрисии, действия Apple на книжном рынке Европы и, может быть, России.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barnes &amp; Noble заходит в Европу через Германию</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-03-29-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 08:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-03-29-b/</guid>
      <description>Just as Amazon is launching a new Kindle (but not the Fire tablet, yet) in Europe, one of its big competitors is taking one more step in its bid to enter the European market: Barnes &amp;amp; Noble has incorporated a new company, Barnes &amp;amp; Noble Digital Media GmbH, in Germany.
 via techcrunch.com
В Германии B&amp;amp;N уже работает с Thalia. Будет и тут конкурировать с Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony так-таки открывает книжный магазин для Европы</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-09-05-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 13:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-09-05-1/</guid>
      <description>Reader Store first rolled out in North America back in 2006 and in Sony’s native Japan in 2010.
Now a UK launch is planned for October 2011, with Germany and Austria planned by year’s end and France, Italy and Spain early in 2012. Further new markets are also on the cards.
The launch dovetails with the WiFi-enabled new Reader e-reader Sony announced at IFA in Berlin, which has a touch-screen and pinch-zoom text resizing and is lighter than Kindle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Европа: 15% к 2015 году</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-08-24-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 12:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-08-24-b/</guid>
      <description>Futuresource Consulting, a UK-based consulting firm, published the research on e-books and e-readers. “Despite all this rapid growth in demand for e-books in Western Europe, the market is still in its infancy, representing less than 1 percent of total consumer spending on books,” Futuresource market analyst Fiona Hoy said. “Moving forward, there are enormous opportunities within the market and our forecasts show Western European e-book revenues will reach €1.6 billion by 2015, accounting for 15% of total book spend and representing one out of every five books sold in the region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Европейский проект Доступных регистров правовой информации и работ-сирот</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-06-14-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 11:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-06-14-a/</guid>
      <description>Developed by a European consortium coordinated by the Italian Publishers Association (AIE), ARROW — Accessible Registries of Rights Information and Orphan Works — is a system to help libraries with the identification of rights status and rightsholders in digital library programs. ARROW is based on a pro-active search of rightsholders for works eligible for inclusion in any digitization program, and indirectly is a tool for the identification of so-called “orphan works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Россия не одинока. Европейцы тоже тормоза на эл. рынке</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-06-14-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 11:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-06-14-d/</guid>
      <description>Looking at the way the US market developed, it is clear that publishers were able to adapt to the changing face of digital publishing extremely fast, making a lot of content available in a very short time frame. It is also clear that European publishers are unable to do this. Looking at the Dutch market, it is the lack of content that is one of the main road blocks to a healthy e-book market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kobo получила $50 млн на экпансию в Европу</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-04-19-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 19:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-04-19-a/</guid>
      <description>Kobo kicked off its European expansion last week, with the announcement of its plans to launch local content stores in Germany. Local additions are also coming for Spain, France, Italy and the Netherlands.
Some of Kobo’s recent achievements include:
 An e-book store that has more than 2.3 million e-books, newspapers and magazines. More than 3.2 million users, more than 1 million new users in the past 90 days.   via emoney.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Европейский библиотека растёт</title>
      <link>/posts/2009-12-17-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 22:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2009-12-17-a/</guid>
      <description>Europeana’s collection of online European heritage passed the 5 million mark in early December, taking the multilingual digital library, museum and archive over halfway to its target of 10 million searchable items in 2010.
Portraits of notable Polish figures, including astronomer Copernicus and composer Frederic Chopin are among the newest additions to Europeana – part of some 257,000 images, texts, videos and sounds that were submitted by regional groups across Poland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
