<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LatAm on Новости электронного книгоиздания</title>
    <link>/tags/latam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LatAm on Новости электронного книгоиздания</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 08:50:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/latam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Kindle Store открылся в Мексике</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-08-30-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 08:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2013-08-30-b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New Kindle Store offers over 2 million eBooks sold in Mexican Pesos, including the most Spanish language best sellers, more than 1,500 free books in Spanish, and hundreds of thousands of exclusive titles, including works from authors like José Emilio Pacheco, Elena Poniatowska, Sergio Pitol and Carlos Monsivais, as well as comic books from Mafalda and Familia Burrón&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://phx.corporate-ir.net/phoenix.zhtml?c=176060&amp;amp;p=irol-newsArticle&amp;amp;ID=1850669&amp;amp;highlight=&#34;&gt;Amazon Media Room: Press Releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon зашёл на самый большой испаноязычный рынок 70 тыс испаноязычных книг, 2 млн в общем каталоге и 1399 песо (3485 руб.) за простенький Kindle. 115 млн человек. Уровень проникновения интернета, правда, не очень высокий в сравнении с другими странами Латинской Америки — &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/7YLLdH&#34;&gt;всего около 40%&lt;/a&gt;. Но и 47 млн пользователей — тоже неплохо. Когда уж в России-то?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Бразильское книжное Рождество: Kobo, Google и Amazon</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-12-06-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 10:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2012-12-06-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Практически в один день в Бразилии открылись местные сайты трёх гигантов рынка электронных книг. И это при том, что электронного ассортимента на португальском ещё меньше, чем на русском. Обидно.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon ждут в Бразилии в конце года</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-07-02-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 14:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2012-07-02-b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon thinks it could quickly dominate Brazil’s e-book market with the Kindle, boosting sales of electronic books to 15 per cent of the publishing market in the first year of operations from 0.5 per cent currently, the industry source said.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon hopes to grab 90 per cent of Brazil’s e-book market, the source added, in part because many Brazilians already download content from its site using readers they bought abroad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
